<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
    xml:id="Identity-Service-Concepts-e1362">
    <title>Identity Service Concepts</title>
    <para>The OpenStack Identity Service has the following key
        concepts: </para>
    <table rules="all">
        <caption>Identity Service Concepts</caption>
        <thead>
            <tr>
                <th>Concept</th>
                <th>Description</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <td><para>User</para></td>
                <td><para>A digital representation of a person, system, or service that
                        uses OpenStack cloud services. OpenStack
                        Identity authentication services validate that
                        an incoming request is being made by the user
                        who claims to be making the call. </para>
                    <para>Users have a login and may be assigned
                        tokens to access resources. Users may be
                        directly assigned to a particular tenant and
                        behave as if they are contained in that
                        tenant.</para></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td><para>Credentials</para></td>
                <td>
                    <para>Data that belongs to, is owned by, and
                        generally only known by a user that the user
                        can present to prove their identity. </para>
                    <para>Examples include: <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>A matching username and
                                   password</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>A matching username and API
                                   key</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>A token that was issued to you
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td><para>Authentication</para></td>
                <td>
                    <para>In the context of OpenStack Identity
                        Service, the act of confirming the identity of
                        a user or the truth of a claim. OpenStack
                        Identity Service confirms that an incoming
                        request is being made by the user who claims
                        to be making the call by validating a set of
                        claims that the user is making. </para>
                    <para>These claims are initially in the form of a
                        set of credentials (username &amp; password,
                        or username and API key). After initial
                        confirmation, OpenStack Identity Service
                        issues the user a token, which the user can
                        then provide to demonstrate that their
                        identity has been authenticated when making
                        subsequent requests. </para>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Token</td>
                <td>
                    <para>An arbitrary bit of text that is used to
                        access resources. Each token has a scope that
                        describes which resources are accessible with
                        it. A token may be revoked at anytime and is
                        valid for a finite duration. </para>
                    <para>While OpenStack Identity Service supports
                        token-based authentication in this release,
                        the intention is for it to support additional
                        protocols in the future. The intent is for it
                        to be an integration service foremost, and not
                        a aspire to be a full-fledged identity store
                        and management solution. </para>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Tenant</td>
                <td>
                    <para>A container used to group or isolate
                        resources and/or identity objects. Depending
                        on the service operator, a tenant can map to a
                        customer, account, organization, or project.
                    </para>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td><para>Service</para></td>
                <td>
                    <para>An OpenStack service, such as Compute
                        (Nova), Object Storage (Swift), or Image
                        Service (Glance). A service provides one or
                        more endpoints through which users can access
                        resources and perform operations. </para>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td><para>Endpoint</para></td>
                <td>
                    <para>An network-accessible address, usually
                        described by a URL, where a service may be
                        accessed. If using an extension for templates,
                        you can create an endpoint template, which
                        represents the templates of all the consumable
                        services that are available across the
                        regions. </para>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td><para>Role</para></td>
                <td>
                    <para>A personality that a user assumes when
                        performing a specific set of operations. A
                        role includes a set of right and privileges. A
                        user assuming that role inherits those rights
                        and privileges. </para>
                    <para>In OpenStack Identity Service, a token that
                        is issued to a user includes the list of roles
                        that user can assume. Services that are being
                        called by that user determine how they
                        interpret the set of roles a user has and to
                        which operations or resources each role grants
                        access. </para>
                </td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
</section>
